M. ASHISH REDDY

Email ID: ashishreddy2222@gmail.com Phone Number: (+91) 6309540172

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ashish-r-2b4091b7/

GitHub: https://github.com/ashish-reddy-20-08

Portfolio: github.io/Ashish-portfolio/

SUMMARY

1.5 years of industry experience with excellent communication and agile team working experience. Working with companies has given me an immense learning and extensive real-life problem-solving ability.

Skills

Python | Data science | Tableau | Machine Learning SQL | Artificial Intelligence | Data structures and Algorithms | HTML | CSS | Java Script.

COURSE WORK

Linux | Software Engineering

EXPERIENCE

Contributor in GWOC'21 Sep 2021 - Jan 2022 *GirlScript Foundation*

- Top 1 contributor in the field of Machine Learning and among the top 3 in the field of Data science with python and R programming.
- Contributed towards making audio, video and documentation of projects and successfully merged 140+ pull requests.

Data Analyst Intern May 2021 – Jul 2021

Tare Zameen Foundation

- Worked on web scrapping of the data from webpages.
- Created a model with 85 percentage accuracy as a team which suggests best colleges for class 12 students, based on their interests.

EDUCATION

B. TECH (COMPUTER SCIENCE ENGINEERING) (HONS.) 2019 - 2023

Lovely Professional University, Punjab.

SENIOR SECONDARY: 2017 - 2019

Telangana state board, Sri Chaitanya, Hyderabad.

MATRICULATION: 2004 – 2017

CBSE, Little Flower School, Uppal, Hyderabad.

RESPONSIBILITIES:

Worked as the Chief operating officer of Creative
Beast EMS Pvt Ltd
Sep 2019 – Jun 2021

Worked as the Campus Ambassador of Reach
Technologies
Feb 2021 - Mar 2021

- Worked as the Influencer at Leher App on the topics "Motivation and Commitment is the key to success", "Career Guidance".
 Jul 2021 – Aug 2021
- Worked as the community development intern at VRO(Hyd.)
 May 2020 – Jul 2020
- Lead anchor and yellow house captain at Little Flower School 2015 - 2017

PROJECTS:

Speech Emotion Recognition

Aim: Analysing the emotion of a person.

Details: Used the visualization techniques like waveplot and spectrogram, used data augmentation techniques, and also extracted the features using libROSA library. Outcomes: Created a pre-trained model with an accuracy

of 61 percentage.

Link:Speech-Emotion-Recognition

Portfolio website

Aim: Building a website to show case accomplishments. Details: Used the tools HTML, CSS, and Java Script to build my website

Outcome: A responsive website show casing my career achievements to date.

Link: Ashish-portfolio

Time-series-data-analysis

Aim: Analysis of the time series data using different techniques

Details: Used various models like FB-Prophet, ARIMA Model, VAR Model, and SARIMAX Model.

Outcomes: This project has the collection of the various time series techniques put together and helps to choose the best model for the data.

Link:Time-series-data-analysis

Tableau project on air travel data of the San Francisco airport

Aim: Creating an interactive dashboard for analysing data. Details: Used the tableau public functions to create the dashboard.

Outcomes: This dashboard helps the users to analyse the traffic at the San Francisco airport.

Link of the dashboard: Tableau Public

Spam and Ham Mail detection

Aim: Analysing a given mail is spam or ham.

Details: Used NLP to clean the data and applied the multinomial naïve bayes theorem.

Outcomes: Created a model that has scored an accuracy of 96.94 percentage accuracy on the test data.

Link:spam-ham-detection

ACHIEVEMENTS:

- Participated in the hack4woman hackathon at Girl Script India Summit'2021.
- Participated in the Ideathon conducted by Lovely Professional University, 2021.
- Participated in the hackathon conducted by JumpStart, 2021.
- Secured 3rd prize in All India Level storytelling competition at Hunar 2.0, 2021.
- Computer Wizard of the year by TIMES OF INDIA,2017.
- Secured 3rd prize in ALL INDIA LEVEL ONLINE QUIZ, "EUREKA", 2020.
- Participated in the TECH QUIZ in Prep Bytes O-Mega Fest 2021.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Data Science with Python, Simplilearn, 2021.
- What is Data Science & DS toolbox Coursera, 2021.
- Complete python Bootcamp from Zero to Hero, **Udemy**, 2021.